Summary

Senior software engineer with strong and wide-ranging technical competencies, able to work with a minimum of supervision, quickly and to a high standard. I have 10 years of commercial work experience across several different industries including financial services, insurance and health.

Skills

- Expert: Typescript, ES6, React, React Native, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Node, NPM, Yarn, Jest, Webpack
- Proficient: AWS DynamoDB, Serverless, GraphQL, Gitlab CI, GitHub Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, SQL

Work Experience

<u>Software Consultant</u> **UBS (contract)** – London

2022 - Present

 Dashboard implementation project, split Developer/Dev Ops role where I help build the application in React/TypeScript and the CI/CD pipeline to deploy the app using Gitlab CI, Docker and Kubernetes

<u>Senior Software Engineer</u> RU

RUNNA – London

Feb 22 - August 22

 Working as part of a small development team at a startup building out a mobile app for personalised run coaching. App built with Typescript, React Native, Apollo GraphQL, DynamoDB, Lambda and Serverless.

Senior Software Engineer

Nationwide Building Society - London

2019 – 2022

• Helped build a new business savings mobile app in React Native powered by cloud native technologies. As the senior engineer on my feature team I led development on key payments and accounting service features.

Front End Developer

WebMD - London

2017 - 201

 Working as part of a large development team alongside designers, writers, editors to develop websites and apps for medical professionals.

Front End Developer

AIMIA – Sydney

2016

• I was the principal Front End developer in an agile environment alongside a .NET team to develop a fully compliant WCAG website for a leading Australian bank.

UI Developer

IAG - Sydney

2014 – 2016

Developing front end applications in an Agile environment working across multiple projects and teams.

Front End Developer

Oakton - Sydney

2014

• Short term contract tasked with improving an existing websites user experience as well as general bug and style fixing. Technologies primarily used during this role were HTML5 and JavaScript.

Front End Developer

Rice Warner - Sydney

2014

JavaScript developer role working on a bespoke, cloud-based and responsive financial planning application developed for a major Australian bank.

Front End Developer

True Alliance - Sydney

2014

Working as a contracted front-end developer on two main projects for multiple globally recognised fashion brands.

Web Developer

Rail Europe - London

2012 - 2014

• Principle web developer within the eCommerce team. Also was a key member in rebranding from 'Rail Europe' to 'Voyages-sncf' including migration of content management systems.

Personal Projects

- 2023 Claremont Gorillas I'm currently building a React Native app for my football team, this allows the players to check fixtures, see player/team stats, notify of their availability for upcoming games and more.
- 2021 **Wembeerly** Prior to the Euro 2020 football championship I and 3 other friends brewed and launched our own beer with proceeds going to charity (Grassroots for Good). I built the website and payments system from scratch using React and Stripe as our payment processor.
- 2019 EMBA I built a brochure website for a friend who launched their own alcoholic drink called EMBA, this was built using React (GatsbyJS) and Node.

Education